

Luca Tarozzi
tarozzi.l@gmail.com
web:lucatarozzi.
github.io
(+39) 340/2560791

Address Via Camatta 1 41121 Modena Italy

Luca Tarozzi

Mechanical engineer, Ph.D.

About Me I am a Master of Science and Ph.D. in Mechanical Engineering. Since 2007 I am responsible for the R&D activities at the company Bettati antincendio srl located in Reggio Emilia (Italy). My actual activities are focused in the design, testing and certification of fire suppression componts (e.g. container valve for gas suppression system, spray nozzle for watermist system) and I am also involved in audit activities related to FPC, ISO9001, TPED and PED certifications. Moreover I have experience in firefighting system design according to European and international standards and and I have been appointed as expert at UNI and CEN committee for standardization. During the doctorate I have also gained an experience in applied physics with particular reference to heat transfer and the development of experimental tests and data acquisition campaign (velocity, pressure and temperature measurements with a particular focus on infrared thermography). I am author of more than 20 publications at an international or national level. In 2006-2007 I have taught classes in the frame of courses related to thermodynamics and heat transfer at the University of Modena and Reggio Emilia and later I have been speaker to many seminars and conferences related to fire suppression systems.

Education

2004 - 2007, University of Modena and Reggio Emilia, IT Ph.D in Mechanical engineering

1996 - 2002, University of Modena and Reggio Emilia, IT Master degree in Mechanical engineering

2000 - 2001, University of Exeter, UK Erasmus project at Engineering department

1991 - 1996, Scientific high school "Wiligelmo", Modena, IT Graduation

Experience

Novembre 2007 - present, *R&D engineer*, Bettati antincendio, Reggio Emilia, IT

Detailed achievements:

- Learned how to manage R&D project related to the design and testing of mechanical components of fire fighting systems (e.g. nozzles, valves, fire pumps units);
- Learned how to arrange real scale fire test in order to challenge fire extinguishing systems;
- Learned how to design fire extinguishing systems and manage system installation and commissioning;
- Learned how to achieve component certification according to CE standards and international quality mark (e.g. VdS or UL approval).
 VdS and UL are quality mark internationally recognized for fire fighting systems and components;
- Learned how to managed quality ISO 9001 and FPC (Factory Production Control) audits;
- Learned how to drive company interests at national (UNI) and international (CEN, ISO) standardization meeting;



Luca Tarozzi
tarozzi.l@gmail.com
web:lucatarozzi.
github.io
(+39) 340/2560791

Address Via Camatta 1 41121 Modena Italy

• Learned how to arrange seminars and conferences related to fire suppression systems.

Novembre 2006 - November 2007, *Research grant*, University of Modena e Reggio Emilia, Department of Mechanical and Civil Engineering, Modena, IT

Research activity in industrial physic group. Main research topic: Formulation and validation of a model and a numerical code for simulation of an hydrogen distribution network.

March 2004 - March 2007, *PhD*, University of Modena e Reggio Emilia, Department of Mechanical and Civil Engineering, Modena, IT Detailed achievements:

- Gained an experience in applied physics with particular reference to heat transfer and the development of experimental tests and data acquisition campaign (velocity, pressure and temperature measurements with a particular focus on infrared thermography);
- More than 20 publications at an international or national level;
- Taught classes in the frame of courses related to thermodynamics and heat transfer at the University of Modena and Reggio Emilia.

March 2003 - March 2004, *Mechanical engineer*, Tecnodinamica snc, Rubiera, Reggio Emilia, IT

Gained experience on autocad drawings and spare parts technical documentation (main customer CNH).

Skills, comptences and interests

Languages

- Italian: mother tongue;
- English: advanced level in understanding, writing and speaking.

Programming and computer software

Microsoft office
 LaTex
 Matlab
 Linux
 Autocad
 Octave
 Python

Hardware

National instru Arduino
 Raspberry PI ments

Interpersonal skills

Flexible, open minded, proactive, self motivated, good in collaboration and working in team, responsible, accurate and detail oriented.

Professional interests

Mechanical engineering, Mechatronics, Applied physics, Heat transfer modeling, Fire fighting equipment and components, Fire fighting system desig, Test and experiments

Personal interests

Piano, Chess, Music, Art, Bicycle

Publications, Speaking and more details

External references

Publication/speaking: https://lucatarozzi.github.io

More details: https://www.linkedin.com/in/luca-tarozzi-47b02446/